Palestine
Marist College
Palestine
1789 1984
Marist Archives and Special Collections 3399 North Road, Poughkeepsie, New York 12601
Lowell Thomas
2.1.1.2.1.2
1203 Linear feet
Items in this collection do not circulate and may be used in-house only.
Glass Plate Negatives; Palestine
- Lowell Thomas Papers
  - Graphic Material, 2
    - Photographs, 2.1
      - Glass Plate Negatives, 2.1.1
        - Lowell Thomas, 2.1.1.2
          - Indexed Photographs, 2.1.1.2.1
            - Palestine, 2.1.1.2.1.2
                - Airplane on ground with pilot in front cockpit and Lowell Thomas operating a Graphlex camera standing in the rear cockpit, 1918; 1 (Box 1266)
                5x7
                film
                - Lowell Thomas in pith helmet sits and servant stands in front of tent with cameras and other equipment on the ground, 1918; 2
                - Lowell Thomas in pith helmet sits and servant stands in front of tent with cameras and other equipment on the ground [same as 2-3], 1918; 3
                4x5
                - Lowell Thomas and servant sitting in front of tent with cameras and other equipment on the ground, 1918; 4
                - Egyptians carrying grain, Kantara, 1918; 5
                - Building bridge over Suez Canal, 1918; 6
                - Supplies at Kantara, ammunition depot, 1918; 7
                - Sheds and supply depots at Kantara, 1918; 8
                - Milk and Honey Express Railroad, 1918; 9
                - Explosive shells, Kantara, 1918; 10
                - Railway station, Kantara, 1918; 11
                - Red Cross train, Kantara, 1918; 12
                - Graveyard, sunset, 1918; 13
                - Sick camels [same image as 2-71], 1918; 14
                - Baby camel and Arab, 1918; 15
                - Mad camel frothing at mouth, 1918; 16
                - Baby camel [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: A baby dromedary two hours old], 1918; 17
                - Camel hospital, unidentified major pointing at camel’s hump, 1918; 18
                - Camel hospital among trees, 1918; 19
                - View from airplane of Suez Canal at Kantara (aerial view), 1918; 20
                3.5x5
                - View from airplane of Kantara, best view (aerial view), 1918; 21
                - Suez Canal from airplane, best view (aerial view), 1918; 22
                - View from airplane of sand dunes in the Sinai Desert (aerial view), 1918; 23
                - View from airplane of airplane in flight (aerial view), 1918; 24
                - View from airplane of Desert Wadis (aerial view), 1918; 25
                3.5x4.5
                - Site of Solomon’s Temple, 1918; 26
                - View from airplane of demarcation line between the desert and Palestine (aerial view), 1918; 27
                - View from airplane of military camp, roads going in all directions (aerial view), 1918; 28
                - View from airplane of a village (aerial view), 1918; 29
                - View from airplane of a village (aerial view), 1918; 30
                - View from airplane of aerodrome at plains of Sharon (aerial view), 1918; 31
                - Lowell Thomas in cockpit of airplane, 1918; 32
                - View from airplane of Kantara, second best view (aerial view), 1918; 33
                - View from airplane of coast, looking through airplane’s guy wires (aerial view), 1918; 34
                - View from airplane of Jaffa, looking through airplane’s guy wires (aerial view), 1918; 35
                - View from airplane of General Edmund Allenby’s army encampment near the Suez Canal (aerial view), 1918; 36
                - View from airplane of a military camp, roads go out in all directions (aerial view), 1918; 37
                - Lowell Thomas and military officer examining a Turkish skull in abandoned trench, 1918; 38
                - Beersheba, two men riding camels in foreground, 1918; 39
                - Captains Seward and Emmett standing beside an airplane, 1918; 40
                - Lowell Thomas (with back to camera) and military officer at Abraham’s Well, 1918; 41
                - Mosque at Beersheba, 1918; 42
                - Hindu officer on camel [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: A racing dromedary from India], 1918; 43
                - Wrecked railroad bridge, Lowell Thomas (second from left with back to camera) and military officers in foreground, 1918; 44
                - View of Hebron from cemetery, 1918; 45
                - Several people sit alongside pool at Hebron, 1918; 46
                - Abraham’s Oak, man standing in foreground, 1918; 47
                - Nile water well at Khan Yunis, 1918; 48
                - Arab school, large group of students with teachers, 1918; 49
                - Arab school, Lowell Thomas and military officer stand behind a large group of students with teachers, 1918; 50
                - Mount Pisgah where Moses saw the Promised Land, Lowell Thomas and military officer looking off into the distance, 1918; 51
                - Panorama of Gaza, 1918; 52
                - Ruins of Gaza, automobile with military driver in foreground, 1918; 53
                - Ruined minaret of Great Mosque at Gaza, 1918; 54
                - Interior view of the ruins of the Great Mosque at Gaza, 1918; 55
                - Main street of Gaza in ruins, men on horseback in center of street, 1918; 56
                - Street in ruins approaching the Great Mosque of Gaza, 1918; 57
                - Ruins of Gaza, Bedouin kneeling beside shell hole, 1918; 58
                - Military officer stands amid the ruins of the Great Mosque at Gaza, 1918; 59
                - Hole in dome of mosque at Gaza, two men on horseback in road, 1918; 60
                - Blind man and young boy with donkey among ruins of Gaza, 1918; 61
                - Camel hospital from distance, 1918; 62
                - Camel lines, Egyptian stands near large tree in foreground, 1918; 63
                - Camel lines, 1918; 64
                - Long camel lines, 1918; 65
                - Sick camels [same image as 2-13], 1918; 66
                - Camel hospital, 1918; 67
                - Camel lines in Jerusalem, 1918; 68
                - Operating on camels, 1918; 69
                - Camel in operating pen at hospital, 1918; 70
                - Egyptians fixing camel pack saddles [same image as 2-80], 1918; 71
                - Arab men with camels, 1918; 72
                - Baggage camels, 1918; 73
                - Egyptian carrying blanket roll, 1918; 74
                - Egyptians fixing camel pack saddles [same image as 2-76], 1918; 75
                - Army camp, 1918; 76
                - Army tents at sunset [same image 2-84], 1918; 77
                - Indian troops at Bir Salem, 1918; 78
                - Army tents at sunset [same image as 2-82], 1918; 79
                - Hebron, tomb of Machpelah, 1918; 80
                - Distant view of General Edmund Allenby’s headquarters, 1918; 81
                - Ramleh corner, 1918; 82
                - Moslem funeral at Ramleh, several soldiers at right, close-up, 1918; 83
                - British soldiers at Moslem funeral at Ramleh, Crusader Tower in background, 1918; 84
                - Racobeth from distance, 1918; 85
                - Mayor’s house, Racobeth, 1918; 86
                - Jewish children, 1918; 87
                - Australian soldier with young Jewish girl, 1918; 88
                - Tiled roofs of houses in a Jewish village, 1918; 89
                - Richon, 1918; 90
                - Richon woman, 1918; 91
                - Piles of oranges, many people milling about, Jaffa, 1918; 92
                - Four Scottish soldiers reading a church notice, Jaffa, 1918; 93
                - Jerusalem street scene inside Jaffa Gate, 1918; 94
                - Mill at Auja, 1918; 95
                - Auja River and mill, soldier seated in foreground, 1918; 96
                - Two Scottish soldiers looking across Auja River, 1918; 97
                - Auja River crossing, 1918; 98
                - Street scene, Petach Riquath [?], 1918; 99
                - Bombarded library, 1918; 100
                - Mayor Sachs [Sacks?] [Saxe?] of Racobeth, 1918; 101
                - Lowell Thomas’s tent, 1918; 102
                - Lowell Thomas’s tent, 1918; 103
                - Two Australians standing on Mughar Hill, 1918; 104
                - Many British soldiers sitting by a roadside, 1918; 105
                - Line of camels and men walking along a hairpin bend in the road, 1918; 106
                - Line of camels, trucks and men moving along a hairpin bend in the road, 1918; 107
                - Automobile passing through Judean Hills, 1918; 108
                - Truck carrying wine breaks down, 1918; 109
                - Truck carrying Richon wine breaks down, 1918; 110
                - Automobile on road to village near Jerusalem, 1918; 111
                - Jerusalem, near Mosque of Omar, 1918; 112
                - Jerusalem street scene, near Mosque of Omar, 1918; 113
                - Mosque of Omar, Indian on guard, 1918; 114
                - Bedouin hospital, 1918; 115
                - Mosque of Omar, sunset, 1918; 116
                - British soldiers walking about temple site (al-Aqsa Mosque), 1918; 117
                - Al-Aqsa Mosque, 1918; 118
                - Al-Aqsa Mosque, 1918; 119
                - Al-Aqsa Mosque, 1918; 120
                - Tree, Arak, 1918; 121
                - Disabled British tank, soldiers on horseback near Gaza, 1918; 122
                - Patrol of Ford automobiles in desert (Lowell Thomas note: This goes with Arabian negatives), 1918; 123
                - Jerusalem from Mount of Olives, close-up, 1918; 124
                - British soldiers at Mount of Olives, 1918; 125
                - Jerusalem from Mount of Olives, British army camp in foreground, soldiers signaling with flags, 1918; 126
                - Lowell Thomas pointing as he sits in a Ford automobile, Jordan Valley and Dead Sea, distant view, 1918; 127
                - Lowell Thomas sitting in a Ford automobile peers through a telescope, Jordan Valley and Dead Sea, distant view, 1918; 128
                - Stiftung ceiling, mosaic of Kaiser Wilhelm II and Kaiserin Victoria., 1918; 129
                - Damascus Gate, Jerusalem, 1918; 130
                - Russian Spire, close-up, Mount of Olives, 1918; 131
                - Russian Spire, close-up, Mount of Olives, 1918; 132
                - Russian Spire, Mount of Olives, 1918; 133
                - Cloud effect over Jerusalem, 1918; 134
                - Stiftung from distance, 1918; 135
                - Two British soldiers stand before statues of Kaiser Wilhelm II and Kaiserin Victoria, 1918; 136
                - Statues of Kaiser Wilhelm II and Kaiserin Victoria, 1918; 137
                - Stiftung ceiling, mosaic of Kaiser Wilhelm II and Kaiserin Victoria, 1918; 138
                - Mosaic of King David, 1918; 139
                - Road from Stiftung up to Mount of Olives, 1918; 140
                - Stiftung Chapel, 1918; 141
                - Mosaic of Christ on throne, 1918; 142
                - Lowell Thomas, in uniform, holding starving beggar child, 1918; 143
                - British soldiers on guard over Garden of Gethsemane, 1918; 144
                - Camel caravan passing Garden of Gethsemane, 1918; 145
                - Jerusalem rag picker, 1918; 146
                - Bishop, wife and three orphans, 1918; 147
                - Six beggar children sitting on street in Jerusalem, 1918; 148
                - Beggar child, rag about head, 1918; 149
                - Bishop and many beggar children, 1918; 150
                - Squatting Bedouin child, 1918; 151
                - Frederick Vester and little girl with one eye, 1918; 152
                - Turkish proclamation, 1918; 153
                - Mrs. Anna [?] Spafford, her daughter and adopted son, Jacob, 1918; 154
                - Mrs. Anna [?] Spafford, her daughter and adopted son, Jacob, 1918; 155
                - Bertha Vester and many women from Russia and Armenia stand on a balcony, 1918; 156
                - Bertha Vester with women and children, 1918; 157
                - Bertha Vester and veiled woman, 1918; 158
                - Bertha Vester and veiled woman, 1918; 159
                - Bedouin shaving boy’s head, 1918; 160
                - Bedouin shaving boy’s head, 1918; 161
                - Suez Canal, pontoons, 1918; 162
                - Russian hospital, 1918; 163
                - Governor’s Palace, Jerusalem, 1918; 164
                - Jaffa Gate ceremony, 1918; 165
                - Jaffa Gate, British soldier at guard house, Arab man walking toward camera, 1918; 166
                - Jaffa Gate, British soldier at guard house, man holding umbrella walking toward camera, 1918; 167
                - Jaffa Gate, British soldier at guard house, three men walking toward camera, 1918; 168
                - Jaffa Gate, British soldier at guard house, people and camels in street, 1918; 169
                - Jaffa Gate, British soldier at guard house, three men in tall hats walking toward camera, 1918; 170
                - Jerusalem, Mount of Olives, 1918; 171
                - Jaffa Gate, British soldiers at guard house, many people walk in the street, 1918; 172
                - British staff automobiles at Jaffa Gate, 1918; 173
                - British staff automobiles at Jaffa Gate, 1918; 174
                - Man carrying timber, 1918; 175
                - Colonel Camp and three British officers, 1918; 176
                - Group of officers in front of office of military governor of Bethlehem, 1918; 177
                - British soldier seated in Church of Nativity, 1918; 178
                - Palestine, several people working in a field, 1918; 179
                - Duke of Connaught, close-up, 1918; 180
                - Soldiers standing at attention during awards ceremony conducted by the Duke of Connaught, distant view, 1918; 181
                - Duke of Connaught decorating General Boles, 1918; 182
                - Duke of Connaught decorating unidentified soldier, 1918; 1 (Box 1267)
                - Duke of Connaught shaking hands with unidentified soldier who has received a medal, 1918; 2
                - Duke of Connaught shaking hands with unidentified soldier who has received a medal, 1918; 3
                - Lowell Thomas, Duke of Connaught and General Edmund Allenby (leaning forward), 1918; 4
                - Lowell Thomas, Duke of Connaught and General Edmund Allenby (leaning forward), 1918; 5
                8x10
                - General Edmund Allenby with hand on wall, distant, 1918; 6
                - General Edmund Allenby, side view, close-up, 1918; 7
                - General Edmund Allenby, side view, 1918; 8
                - General Edmund Allenby, 1918; 9
                - General Edmund Allenby, 1918; 10
                - General Edmund Allenby and wife, Mabel [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Lord and Lady Allenby], circa 1918; 11
                - Smiling British soldier, 1918; 12
                - Holt tractor rolls off Jericho Road, 1918; 13
                - Jericho Road, 1918; 14
                - Jericho Road, British soldier on mule in foreground, 1918; 15
                - Home of Mary and Martha of Bethany, 1918; 16
                - Brigadier General “Fighting Charlie” Cox approaching Jerusalem in his staff automobile, 1918; 17
                - On road to Jericho, 1918; 18
                - Rachel’s tomb, 1918; 19
                - Rebecca at well scene [same as 2-251A], 1918; 20
                - Rebecca at well scene [same as 2-251], 1918; 21
                - Indians fixing bullets, 1918; 22
                - Indian carrying water, 1918; 23
                - Indian with turban, 1918; 24
                - Indian camp, 1918; 25
                - Second Black Watch, Scotland, on march at Ismalia [should be filed with Egypt], 1918; 26
                - Second Black Watch, Scotland, marching in file, 1918; 27
                - Second Black Watch, Scotland, bagpipes and drums, 1918; 28
                - Second Black Watch, Scotland, group picture of all remaining of original organization in 1914, 1918; 29
                - Second Black Watch, Scotland, group picture of all remaining of original organization in 1914, 1918; 30
                - Second Black Watch, Scotland, sitting in front of pup tent while reading letters from home, 1918; 31
                - Scottish sentry, 1918; 32
                - British tents in Zionist fields, 1918; 33
                - Camp of Zionists in eucalyptus grove, 1918; 34
                - Arab man, 1918; 35
                - Arab man, close-up, 1918; 36
                - Lieutenant Ridley, 1918; 37
                - Major on tall camel, commander of hospital, 1918; 38
                - Major “V. C.” Smith, commander of Australian Camel Corps, 1918; 39
                - Major “V. C.” Smith atop kneeling camel, 1918; 40
                - Tablet on Dog River that refers to the XXI British Army Corps, 1918; 41
                - Scottish soldier with mumps, 1918; 42
                - Scottish soldier with mumps, 1918; 43
                - Australian soldier, 1918; 44
                - Australian soldier, 1918; 45
                - Australian soldier with beard leaning over front of an automobile, other soldiers in background, 1918; 46
                - Two Australian soldiers swapping yarns, 1918; 47
                - General Headquarters, Bir Salim, 1918; 48
                - Jerusalem from Mount of Olives, 1918; 49
                - Horse jumping rail fence, 1918; 50
                - Horse jumping rail fence, distant, 1918; 51
                - Horse jumping race, 1918; 52
                - New Zealander Colonel Mackesy, 1918; 53
                - New Zealand Maori soldiers standing in front of tents, 1918; 54
                - New Zealand Maori soldiers standing in front of tents, 1918; 55
                - Egyptian Labor Corps with Allenby’s army, 1918; 56
                - Abraham’s Tomb, 1918; 57
                - Abraham’s Tomb, 1918; 58
                - Newspaper cartoon of Lowell Thomas drawn by Sava Botzaritch, 1918; 59
                - Little boy not saluting wearing oversize military hat [Malta], 1918; 60
                - Little boy saluting wearing oversize military hat [Malta], 1918; 61
                - Little boy saluting wearing oversize military hat [Malta], 1918; 62
                - Little boy saluting wearing oversize military hat [Malta], 1918; 63
                - Mohammedan Imam of Jerusalem, 1918; 64
                - Mohammedan Imam of Jerusalem, side view [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: A muezzin calling the faithful to prayer], 1918; 65
                - Porter carrying huge bundle on his back, 1918; 66
                - Arabs boarding train, 1918; 67
                - Three graybeards, 1918; 68
                - Three graybeards seated, 1918; 69
                - Stiftung, full view (Graphlex), 1918; 70
                - Girl with can on head, 1918; 71
                - Girl with bread, 1918; 72
                - Woman with white shawl, side view, 1918; 73
                - Woman with white shawl, 1918; 74
                - Barefoot woman in white shawl, 1918; 75
                - Porter carrying many boxes on his head, 1918; 76
                - Porter carrying many boxes on his head, 1918; 77
                - Porter carrying one huge box on his head, 1918; 78
                - Horse tram, side view, 1918; 79
                - Horse tram, front view, 1918; 80
                - Lowell Thomas, Colonel McCall and dog, and Colonel of Kents [?], 1918; 81
                - Colonel W. F. Stirling and dog, close-up, 1918; 82
                - Colonel W. F. Stirling and dog, close-up, 1918; 83
                - Colonel W. F. Stirling and dog, distant, 1918; 84
                - Major General Sir John Shea, front view, smiling, 1918; 85
                - Major General Sir John Shea, front view, 1918; 86
                - Major General Sir John Shea, side view, 1918; 87
                - British soldiers charging up hill, 1918; 1 (Box 1268)
                - Sikh officer, 1918; 2
                - Sikh officer, 1918; 3
                - Sikh officer, stick in hand, 1918; 4
                - Major General Sir Hodgson and staff, 1918; 5
                - Indian cavalry, front view, 1918; 6
                - Indian cavalry, front view, led by British officer, 1918; 7
                - Indian cavalry going over hill, rear view, 1918; 8
                - Indian cavalry going over hill, rear view, 1918; 9
                - Indian cavalry rounding bend, 1918; 10
                - Main street, Tel Aviv, 1918; 11
                - Porter carrying box, the Palestine Express Railway tracks at left, 1918; 12
                - Porter carrying bolts of cloth, the Palestine Express Railway tracks at left, 1918; 13
                - Porter carrying pile of boards, the Palestine Express Railway tracks at left, 1918; 14
                - Three women, one with face veiled, one dressed in white, one carrying tray on her head, 1918; 15
                - Three women holding hands, one with face veiled, one dressed in white, one carrying tray on her head, 1918; 16
                - Woman with melon on head [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: A peasant woman of Syria], 1918; 17
                - Woman with hay on head, 1918; 18
                - Two barefoot women, one with basket on head, 1918; 19
                - Arab man squinting left eye, close-up [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: A Syrian villager][negative has deteriorated beyond recovery], 1918; 20
                - Colonel Camp, side view, 1918; 21
                - Sir Herbert Samuel, 1918; 22
                - General Ronald Storrs, first governor of Jerusalem, front view [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: General Ronald Storrs, Governor of the Holy City, and modern successor to Pontius Pilate], 1918; 23
                - British soldier on guard at Mount of Olives, veiled woman sits under large tree in left foreground, 1918; 24
                - British soldier on guard at Mount of Olives, large tree in foreground, 1918; 25
                - Mosque of Omar, old man and guide in foreground, 1918; 26
                - Jerusalem panorama with olive grove in foreground, guide and British soldier on wall, 1918; 27
                - Panorama of Jerusalem, guide sitting on tomb, 1918; 28
                - Inside Golden Gate, Jerusalem, 1918; 29
                - Damascus Gate, Jerusalem, 1918; 30
                - Damascus Gate, Jerusalem, [negative is badly deteriorated]; 31
                - Garden of Gethsemane, 1918; 32
                - Garden of Gethsemane, 1918; 33
                - Stiftung from Russian Spire [negative is badly deteriorated], 1918; 34
                - Statue of Kaiser Wilhelm II, Union Jack, 1918; 35
                - Statue of Kaiser Wilhelm II, Union Jack, 1918; 36
                - Statue of Kaiser Wilhelm II, 1918; 37
                - Stiftung Tower, many trees in foreground, 1918; 38
                - Stiftung Tower from roadway, many trees in foreground, 1918; 39
                - Stiftung Tower from roadway, many trees in foreground, 1918; 40
                - Jaffa from Tenderloin, lone Egyptian midway on beach, 1918; 41
                - Jaffa waterfront from rocks, 1918; 42
                - Jaffa waterfront, two children in foreground, 1918; 43
                - Jaffa waterfront, man moving too fast on left, 1918; 44
                - Jaffa waterfront, wireless in foreground, 1918; 45
                - Jaffa waterfront, two children walking in foreground, 1918; 46
                - Jaffa waterfront, masts of sailing ships, 1918; 47